# 這個就是昨天晚上收獲的魚
These are the fish that we caught last night.
# 多吧 哎喲
A lot, isn't it? Ayo!
# 等下我就 把你們先煮啦
You guys will be the first to be cooked in a while.
# 洗一下
Wash you,
# 把你洗乾淨
cleanse you,
# 再來處理
for further processing.
# 我們做一個酸菜魚
We're gonna make a "suan cai yu"
(Suan cai yu. Lit: Boiled fish with pickled mustard greens, usually spicy)
# (沒對白)
# 這個蛇頭魚煮酸菜很好吃的
Snakehead fish is a good ingredient for suan cai yu.
(Suan cai yu. Lit: Boiled fish with pickled mustard greens, usually spicy)
# 先把這個最大條的
Let me start with this largest one.
# 就你先
You're the first one.
# 刮一下這個魚鱗
I'm gonna scrape off the scales.
# 它這個魚鱗好大不好刮
Its scales are too big and are rather hard to remove.
# 用手指來扣才快一點
Fingers might be more efficient.
# 沒拍死 拍死啦
It's still alive. Let me slap it to death!
# 你看 這個魚鱗
Look! The scales...
# 這個不用刮鱗的這個
There's no need to scale this fish.
# 這樣就可以啦 砍成一段段就可以啦
That's it. Chop it up into chunks and it's done.
# 好快的 這個火燒的好快
It's so fast. The fire grows really fast.
# 讓它慢慢燒
Leave it burning for a while.
# 放點這個鹹菜
Put some, this kind of pickles.
# 切大塊有[SIC]點 好夾一點
Cut it into larger pieces. It's easier to take with chopsticks.
# 鹹菜已經搞定啦
The pickles are now ready.
# 你看 搞 搞了一點豆芽回來
Look! I've fetched, fetched some sprouts.
# 這豆芽淋一下水就好啦
The sprouts only need to be rinsed.
# 這個
The,
# 生薑大蒜 洗乾淨就好啦
the ginger and the garlic, wash them and that's it.
# 我們要拍一下這個生薑
We gotta smash the ginger.
# 這個會怕把它拍爆 這個瓷板
I don't wanna break it. It's a porcelain board.
# 你看 這個 準備好這些料等一下
Look! Here, we have these ingredients ready. We'll,
# 我們等一下再來
we'll come back to them in a while.
# 要先把它 那個醎菜抄[SIC]一下
Now let's fry, fry the pickles first.
# 先把這個油
Let me put the oil,
# 放下去
into the wok first.
# 先要炒一下
It needs to be fried for a while.
# 把這個大蒜先放下去炒一下
I put the garlic and fry it for a while.
# 更香
It smells even better.
# 這個差不多香啦
The scents start coming out now.
# 搞點水
Put some water,
# 去燜它
and stew it.
# 哎喲 那麼靚的
Ayo! Why is it so beautiful?
# 都不夠水再加一點
More water. It's not enough.
# 用鍋蓋先蓋著它
Cover it with the lid first.
# 把它煮開然後就放那個魚
I'll put the fish when it boils.
# 把這個魚放下去
Now I put the fish into the wok.
# 有黃鱔有泥鰍 有蛇頭魚
There are eels, loaches and snakehead fish.
# 把這個豆芽也放下去
And the sprouts too
# 加點水 水有點少
Put some more water. The water here is not quite enough.
# 加點鹽
Put some salt.
# 這個鹽要加多一點
We needs a bit more salt,
# 那麼多魚
as we have so many fish.
# 好啦 蓋蓋起來
Alright! Cover it with the lid.
# 用火來
Cook it with fire,
# 猛火來燒它
with strong fire.
# 我把火吹一下 看它沒著啊
I try blowing into the fire. It's not glowing.
# 哎 著啊
Ay! It glows.
# 你看 這個狗還小的時候很胖的
Look! This dog used to be a fat boy when he was small.
# 現在都變
But he's now,
# 瘦狗啦
a skinny dog.
# 那麼瘦
So skinny
# 是不是 你那麼瘦 怎麼搞的
Aren't you? You're so skinny. What happened?
# 不是沒餵你 吃 吃那麼多還那麼瘦
I do feed you well. You, you eat so much but you're still so skinny.
# 吃多一點
Eat more,
# 長成 大胖狗
and be a big fat dog!
# 知不知道
Got it?
# 哇 看你牙齒
Wa! Have a look at your teeth!
# 笑一個
Smile!
# 笑一下
Hey, smile!
# 快點 笑一下
C'mon! Smile!
# 就這樣子的
So this is his smile.
# 這小狗 (註︰沒有原字幕)
This doggy,
# 好臭它的身上
his body is so stinky.
# 沒給它洗澡
I didn't bathe him.
# 我都沒空洗我自己的澡 還幫你洗
I don't even have the time to bathe myself. How can I bathe you?
# 你自己去河裡面洗就行啦
You can simply take a bath yourself in the river.
# 挨著那麼近
It's so close, just outside.
# 自己洗完自己回來啊
Take a bath there and then come back.
# 你看 這個豬種的西紅杮哦 現在都熟啦
Look! These are the tomatoes planted by the pigs. They're now ripe.
# 還有一個不是很紅的
And this one is still a bit green.
# 可以吧 你看
Not bad. Look!
# 有機番茄
Organic tomatoes
# 這邊是有點壞的
It's a bit rotten on this side.
# 嗯
Um!
# 好好吃啊
Tasty!
# 你看 這有籽的哦 我也種一棵
Look! Here are seeds. Let me plant a tomato as well.
# 種在這裡
I plant it here.
# 只有一個 額 多一個我給你吃
I have just one. Eh, I'll give you one if there's another.
# 全來啦 它們
They're, all here.
# 全部還沒熟
The rest are all green.
# 熟了我再過來
I'll come again when they're ripe.
# 有點辣椒
Here's some chilli.
# 放點辣椒更好哦
It tastes much better with some chilli.
# 這個 快 快好啦
It's, nearly, nearly done.
# 我搞點紅油來 紅紅的顏色更好看
Let me fetch some chilli oil. The red colour makes it look more attractive.
# 加點豆瓣醬去顏色就來啦
With some bean paste sauce, the colour comes.
# 乳白色的顏色
The milky white colour,
# 變成紅油啦
is now changed to the colour of chilli oil.
# 你看 放點芥藍下去
Look! Put some gai lan.
# 乾脆吃火鍋算啦
Why don't we simply make it a hotpot?
# 多搞點
Put some more...
# 看一下 去冰箱裡面找一下有甚麼就放下去啦
Let's see, let's find whatever in the fridge and put it here.
# 懶很煮啦 今天晚飯都不用煮
It saves our cooking time, for the dinner tonight.
# 拿著碗就到這裡吃就行啦
I only need to bring my bowl here for my dinner.
# 甚麼樣的都有
Here's everything.
# 應有盡有 哎喲 忘記啦 知道搞隻鴨子下來
It meets all wishes. Aya! I've forgotten. I should have fetched a duck,
# 放在這裡 一鍋燉了它
then I could put it here, and cook it with everything.
# 看一下熟了沒有
Let's see if it's done.
# 哎呀 你看 這個
Aya! Look! This is,
# 色香味俱全
it's appealing to your eyes, your nose and your taste buds.
# 哎呀 先嘗一下
Aya! Let me have a try.
# 搞一條蛇頭魚
Let me get a snakehead fish.
# 這蛇頭魚喲 這個
This is snakehead fish, this one.
# 薑 薑不要
Ginger. Pass
# 怎麼又一顆薑 不要
Why is there another piece of ginger? Pass
# 你看 這魚可以
Look! The fish, it's not bad.
# 這個湯才是精華
The essence is in the soup.
# 精華中的精華
It's the essence of essence.
# 乳白色的哦
It's milky white, you know.
# 嗯
Um!
# 好好吃哦
It's really tasty!
# 那條泥鰍
The loach...
# 哎呀 好辣哦
Aya! It's so spicy!
# 攝影小哥他肯定吃不了啦
Mr. Cameraman surely can't stand it.
# 這蛇頭魚 很嫩的這個肉哦
The snakehead fish, its meat is really tender.
# 而且沒有甚麼小骨頭
And there are hardly any small bones.
# 小狗懷孕啦
The doggy is pregnant.
# 多吃點魚骨頭
Eat more fish bones!
# 你看 這鍋裡面啊
Look! Inside this wok...
# 好香啊 看上去都香
It smells so good. I can tell by my eyes.
# 你看 這個味道很好的 這個味道
Look! The taste is really good, this taste,
# 特別是這個湯的味道
especially the taste of the soup.
# 濃濃的味道
It's so rich,
# 魚肉味
rich flavour of fish.
# 這蛇頭魚
This snakehead fish,
# 這個蛇頭魚 很好吃的這種蛇頭魚
this snakehead fish, this kind of snakehead fish is really tasty.
# 它肉很緊
Its meat is very firm.
# 特別好吃
And it's exceptionally tasty.
# 我很喜歡吃這個蛇頭魚
I like snakehead fish very much.
# 小黑 口水都流出來啦
Blacky is drooling.
# 這魚頭給公狗給你吃 燙不燙 哈哈
This fish head, it's for the big boy. It's for you. Is it hot? Ha ha!
# 很燙
It is!
# 嗯 這小黑狗
Um! This black doggy,
# 以前它是
used to be,
# 爆炸頭 現在都不爆炸啦
very fussy. But he's now no more fussy at all.
# 太多狗啦
Here are too many dogs.
# 沒辦法
He just can't,
# 沒辦法做王
can't be the alpha.
# 小黑 口水流出來啦
Blacky! She's drooling again.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 直接當晚飯吃啦 搞點飯就直接這樣吃算啦
It will be my dinner. I'll get some rice and it will be my dinner right away.
# 就不要煮菜啦
Then I don't need any other dishes.
# 又可以省一點 省一點煤氣
I can also save some, save some gas.